# Web & Mobile Backend & Frontend Full Stack Developer

Contractor - MaryLine Engineers E.I.R.L

Prof. Romel Gomez

romel@maryline.io
(+51) 980653479

https://www.linkedin.com/in/romelgomez/
https://github.com/romelgomez

https://calendly.com/romel-maryline/30min

Romel is a skilled backend & frontend developer with over 10 years of experience, with a track record of building high-value software solutions. Experienced with tests, and familiar with microservices. He loves collaborating with multidisciplinary teams, delivering exceptional products, and continually seeking to learn new technologies. He seeks a position to bring a combination of technical expertise and forward-thinking innovation, ensuring robust and efficient solutions to drive digital transformation and business success.

### **SKILLS**

Back-End	NestJS, Python, Node, Java, Golang
Front-End	NextJS, React, Angular, Typescript, Jquery
Mobile	Expo, React Native, iOS Swift
Search Engines	Algolia, <u>Meilisearch</u>
ORMs	Prisma, TypeORM
Database	PostgreSQL, MySQL, <u>Supabase</u> , Firebase
DevOps	Bash, Docker, Google Cloud
Monorepo	NX.dev, Pantsbuild
APIs	<u>Databricks</u> , Stripe API
SEO	Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager
NoCode	Retool
Design	Figma



















#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Backend Developer**

maergo.com

Mar. 2024 – June. 2024 Austing, TX · Remote

# Responsibilities

- > Build a CVS load view in Retool that accelerates the business data loading time by one week.
- > Build a python scraper that collects and normalizes data from various airlines, and then saves it in Databricks.

# Full Stack Developer

2ulaundry.com

Feb. 2020 – Jan. 2024 Charlotte, NC · Remote

## Responsibilities

- Build and maintain large software platforms using Next.js, and Expo.
- > Implement Algolia as a search engine to perform quick and personalized searches of customers' orders.
- > Develop three React Native apps: one for drivers to track tasks and to-dos, another for customers to schedule pickups and drop-offs, and a third for operations to keep all activities in the facilities in sync.
- > Participate in an on-call rotation to support production systems and investigate issues when they occur.
- > Write high-quality code that is well-tested, secure, and maintainable.
- > Contribute directly to efforts through building features and frameworks, conducting code reviews, and participating in architecture and system design discussions.
- Design and develop solutions able to process large volumes of data.
- Lead and participate in positioning our entire software stack both application and DevOps-related for success as we transition from a startup to a large organization.
- > Be instrumental in the transition from our monolith into Service Oriented Architecture.

# Full Stack Developer

Rextie.com

Sept. 2018 – Feb. 2020 Lima, Peru · On Site

# Responsibilities

- > Provide mentorship and guidance to junior developers, helping them grow their skills and knowledge.
- > Write clean and reusable unit tests, integration, and end-to-end test development.
- > Lead by example in the practice and promotion of excellence in software engineering.

- > Help with root cause analysis, which may identify issues in the reporting, front end or even requirements.
- ➤ Collaborating with various cross-functional teams like design, product management, backend architects, and development teams to validate prototypes and to create elegant, usable, responsive, and interactive interfaces that meet client requirements.

<u>Full Stack Developer</u> MercadoChevere.com Dec. 2014 – Sept. 2018 Maturin, Venezuela · Remote

# Responsibilities

- Implement Algolia as a search engine to perform quick and personalized searches of customers' publications.
- > Design and implement JAVA-based microservices for managing binary tree structured product categories, ensuring scalability and performance.
- > Develop APIs for category management, allowing seamless integration with front-end interfaces and third-party services.
- Architect database schemas to efficiently store and query hierarchical product data, leveraging binary tree structures for optimized access.
- > Collaborate with front-end developers to ensure APIs meet the dynamic needs of the user interface, enhancing user experience.
- > Conduct thorough code reviews to maintain high code quality, focusing on readability, reusability, and maintainability.

**EDUCATION** 

Professor of Informatics University UPEL IPM | Aug. 2016 Maturin, Venezuela

INFORMATION

Languages: Fluent in English and Spanish.

As a dedicated Full Stack Developer with a passion for problem-solving and continuous learning, I am confident in my ability to contribute to your team's success. I look forward to discussing how my skills and experiences align with your needs. Thank you for considering my application.